Guide to the William Manchester Papers, 1934 - 2004
William Manchester Papers1934 - 2004
- Series I: Writings, 1943-1995
  - Books
    - Goodbye, Darkness
      - Original draft
        - 1: Able (Childhood) (Box 105, Folder 10)
        - 2: Baker (Pearl) (Box 105, Folder 11)
        - 3: Charlie (Ghastly Remnants of Its Last Gaunt Garrison) (Box 105, Folder 12)
        - 4: Dog (The Rim of Darkness) (Box 105, Folder 13)
        - 5: Easy (S5[?]) (Box 105, Folder 14)
        - 6: Fox (Canal Slot) (Box 105, Folder 15)
        - 7: George (Tarawa, Hollandia + Biak, Infantryman, Kwaj) (Box 105, Folder 16)
        - 8: How (Infantry, Saipan, Guam) (Box 105, Folder 17)
        - 9: Item (Iwo, Peleliu, Philippines) (Box 105, Folder 18)
        - 10: Jig (Okinawa) (Box 105, Folder 19)
      - Fair copy
        - Front matter, prologue (Box 105, Folder 20)
        - Able (Box 105, Folder 21)
        - Baker (Box 105, Folder 22)
        - Charlie (Box 106, Folder 1)
        - Dog (Box 106, Folder 2)
        - Easy (Box 106, Folder 3)
        - Fox (Box 106, Folder 4)
        - George (Box 106, Folder 5)
        - How (Box 106, Folder 6)
        - Item (Box 106, Folder 7)
        - Jig (Box 106, Folder 8)
        - Author's note (Box 106, Folder 9)
        - Preamble (Box 106, Folder 10)
      - Draft, 1980 Mar
        - Front matter | Preamble | Prologue | Able | Baker | Charlie (Box 106, Folder 11)
        - Dog | Easy (Box 106, Folder 12)
        - Fox | George | How (Box 106, Folder 13)
        - Item | Jig (Box 107, Folder 1)
      - Setting Copy, 1980 Apr
        - Maps (Box 107, Folder 2)
        - Front matter | Preamble | Prologue | Able (Box 107, Folder 3)
        - Baker | Charlie | Dog (Box 107, Folder 4)
        - Easy | Fox | George (Box 107, Folder 5)
        - How | Item (Box 107, Folder 6)
        - Jig | Author's note (Box 107, Folder 7)
      - Author's file set, 1980 May (Box 107, Folder 8-11)
      - Changes and inserts, 1978 Aug-1980 (Box 108, Folder 1)
      - Changes and inserts, 1981 Jan-Jul and undated (Box 108, Folder 2)
      - Little, Brown Set (Box 108, Folder 3-6)
      - Oversize (Box 434)
    - The Last Lion
      General research materials, notes and clumps for the three books have been placed at the beginning.
      - Correspondence
        - 1979 Oct-1983 Apr (Box 108, Folder 7)
        - 1983 May-Jun (Box 108, Folder 8)
        - 1983 Jul-1987 Dec (Box 108, Folder 9)
        - 1988-90 (Box 108, Folder 10)
        - 1991-2004 and undated (Box 108, Folder 11)
        - Little, Brown and Co., 1981 Jul-1989 May (Box 108, Folder 12)
        - Templates - replies to fan mail, 1993-95, 1999 and undated (Box 108, Folder 13)
        - Fan mail/corrections, 1988 Dec-1999 Sep (Box 109, Folder 1)
        - Colville, John, 1981-88 (Box 109, Folder 2)
        - Gilbert, Martin, 1981-95 (Box 109, Folder 3)
        - Harriman, Pamela, 1986-91 (Box 109, Folder 4)
        - Soames, Mary, 1980-84 (Box 109, Folder 5)
        - Soames, Mary, 1985-88 (Box 109, Folder 6)
        - Soames, Mary, 1990-94 (Box 109, Folder 7)
        - Soames, Mary, 1995-97 and undated (Box 109, Folder 8)
        - Williams, Lady Jane, 1982-94 (Box 109, Folder 9)
      - Research materials
        - 1941 (Box 109, Folder 10-11)
        - Acheson: Present at the Creation (Box 109, Folder 12)
        - Ack-Ack (Box 109, Folder 13)
        - Action This Day (Box 109, Folder 14)
        - Alanbrooke (Box 109, Folder 15)
        - Alanbrooke--Turn of the Tide (Box 109, Folder 16)
        - Anglo-Boer War (Box 109, Folder 17)
        - Anzio (Box 109, Folder 18)
        - Assignment: Churchill (Box 109, Folder 19)
        - Aufstieg und Fall des Dritten Reiches (Box 110, Folder 1)
        - Beaver (Box 110, Folder 2)
        - Bezique Rules | de Gaulle obit & biog. sketch | 1931 article: WC: Gentleman Adventurer (Box 110, Folder 3)
        - Black notebook, 1980 Oct (Box 110, Folder 4)
        - The Breaking Wave (Box 110, Folder 5)
        - Bullock: Hitler, A Study in Tyranny (Box 110, Folder 6)
        - Burns - Docs 239-408 (Box 110, Folder 7)
        - Butler: The Art of the Possible (Box 110, Folder 8)
        - Cadogan (Box 110, Folder 9)
        - Cake (Box 110, Folder 10)
        - Cato: Guilty Men (Box 110, Folder 11)
        - The Chief: Ronald Lewen (Box 110, Folder 12)
        - Christienne: Histoire de L'Aviation Militaire Francaise (Box 110, Folder 13)
        - Christienne: History of French Military Aviation (Box 110, Folder 14)
        - Churchill: A Roving Commission (Box 110, Folder 15)
        - Churchill College Archives Centre: Guide (Box 111, Folder 1)
        - Ciano (Box 111, Folder 2)
        - Clippings, 1965, 1980-93 and undated (Box 111, Folder 3)
        - Clippings, 1936, 1981-90 and undated (Box 111, Folder 4)
        - Collier: WWII (Box 111, Folder 5)
        - Coote: WSC's Maxims and Reflections (Box 111, Folder 6)
        - Cooper, Duff (Box 111, Folder 7)
        - Colin Cross: Fall of the British Empire (Box 111, Folder 8-9)
        - Crusade in Europe (Box 111, Folder 10)
        - Dalton (Box 111, Folder 11)
        - Deakin: The Brutal Friendship (Box 111, Folder 12)
        - de Gaulle: The Call to Honour (Box 111, Folder 13)
        - de Gaulle: Complete War Memoirs (Box 111, Folder 14-15)
        - Deighton: Fighter (Box 111, Folder 16)
        - Deighton (Box 112, Folder 1-2)
        - Document Brooks: Bryant (1944-1946); Nicholson [tokum]; Burns, Soldier of Freedom (Box 112, Folder 3)
        - Document "X" (Box 112, Folder 4)
        - Dresden's destruction (Box 112, Folder 5)
        - Duke's War; Coventry; Randolph index (Box 112, Folder 6)
        - Eden #3 (Wavell) (Box 112, Folder 7)
        - Eden: The Reckoning (Box 112, Folder 8)
        - Encyclopaedia Brittanica, 15th ed. (Box 112, Folder 9)
        - Fall of British Empire (Box 112, Folder 10)
        - The Fall of France (Box 112, Folder 11)
        - FDR's undeclared war (Box 112, Folder 12)
        - Fowler: WSC: Philosopher and Statesman (Box 112, Folder 13)
        - Geo V (Box 112, Folder 14)
        - Germains: The Tragedy of Winston Churchill (Box 112, Folder 15)
        - Gilbert: WSC: The Prophet of Truth (Box 112, Folder 16)
        - Goodbye Dolly Gray (Box 112, Folder 17)
        - Halle: Irrepressible Churchill, 18 (Box 112)
        - Harriman, Pamela - speech (Box 113, Folder 1)
        - Higgins: Winston Churchill and the Dardanelles (Box 113, Folder 2)
        - History of WWII--Liddell Hart (Box 113, Folder 3)
        - Hitler: Mein Kampf (Box 113, Folder 4)
        - Hitt's war directives (Box 113, Folder 5)
        - Horne: To Lose a Battle (Box 113, Folder 6)
        - Hunt: On the Spot: An Ambassador Remembers (Box 113, Folder 7)
        - Ironside (Box 113, Folder 8)
        - Ismay (Box 113, Folder 9)
        - Ian Jacob: Finest Hour (Box 113, Folder 10)
        - R.R. James--Eden (Box 113, Folder 11)
        - James: Churchill: A Study in Failure (Box 113, Folder 12)
        - Jock (Box 113, Folder 13)
        - Jones, Thomas (Box 113, Folder 14)
        - Knaur: Aufstieg des Dritte Reiches (Box 113, Folder 15)
        - Lacouture's de Gaulle (Box 113, Folder 16-17)
        - Leslie: Men Were Different (Box 114, Folder 1)
        - Levin: The Pendulum Years (Box 114, Folder 2)
        - Lochner: The Goebbels Diaries (Box 114, Folder 3)
        - Lord Chandos (Box 114, Folder 4)
        - Maass: The Netherlands at War, 1940-1945 (Box 114, Folder 5)
        - MacMillan: The Blast of War (Box 114, Folder 6)
        - MacMillan: Winds of Change, 1914-1939 (Box 114, Folder 7)
        - Majdalany: Battle of El Alamein (Box 114, Folder 8)
        - Maps (Box 114, Folder 9)
        - Marchant (Box 114, Folder 10)
        - Mary's album (Box 114, Folder 11)
        - Mary--Clementine (Box 114, Folder 12)
        - Maxims/reflections (Box 114, Folder 13)
        - McGowan: My Years With Churchill (Box 114, Folder 14)
        - Montgomery of Alamein (Box 114, Folder 15)
        - Moorehead: Churchill in Trial and Triumph (Box 114, Folder 16)
        - Moran (Box 114, Folder 17)
        - "Most secret" (Box 115, Folder 1)
        - Muggeridge: Esquire article (Box 115, Folder 2)
        - Music (Box 115, Folder 3)
        - Nel: Mr. Churchill's Secretary (Box 115, Folder 4)
        - Nicholson: Harold Nicolson's Diaries (Box 115, Folder 5-6)
        - Nicholson (Box 115, Folder 7)
        - Norton: Victorian London (Box 115, Folder 8)
        - Not So Wild a Dream (Box 115, Folder 9)
        - Panter-Downes: London War Notes (Box 115, Folder 10)
        - Peck (Box 115, Folder 11)
        - Periodical index, 1932+ (Box 115, Folder 12)
        - Phillips: The Truman Presidency (Box 116, Folder 1)
        - Prof (Box 116, Folder 2-3)
        - The Prof and the Prime Minister (Box 116, Folder 4)
        - Reader's Guide periodicals re: WSC | Enc 3 re: WSC | Roosevelt + Hopkins re: conferences & bumpf (Box 116, Folder 5)
        - Redburn: Bibliograpy of Works--WSC (Box 116, Folder 6)
        - Reid: Churchill: Townsman of Westerham (Box 116, Folder 7)
        - Revolving (Box 116, Folder 8)
        - Robinson: Piece of Cake (Box 116, Folder 9)
        - Roskill: Hankey: Man of Secrets, Vol. III (Box 116, Folder 10)
        - Sackville-West: The Edwardians (Box 116, Folder 11)
        - Saint-Exupery: Flight to Arras (Box 116, Folder 12)
        - Sheean: Between the Thunder and the Sun (Box 116, Folder 13)
        - Sherwood: Roosevelt & Hopkins (Box 117, Folder 1-2)
        - Shirer: Berlin Diary (Box 117, Folder 3)
        - Shirer: Collapse of the Third Republic (Box 117, Folder 4-5)
        - Shirer: Rise and Fall of the Third Reich (Box 117, Folder 6-7)
        - Soames: Biography of a Marriage (Box 117, Folder 8)
        - Speer, Albert (Box 117, Folder 9)
        - Steele's Lippmann (Box 117, Folder 10)
        - Taylor: The Breaking Wave (Box 118, Folder 1)
        - Thompson: Churchill and Morton (Box 118, Folder 2)
        - Thompson: The Edwardians (Box 118, Folder 3)
        - Thompson: 1940 (Box 118, Folder 4)
        - Thunder/Sun (Box 118, Folder 5)
        - Tillett: London Transport Workers Strike (Box 118, Folder 6)
        - Time, 1936 Mar (Box 118, Folder 7)
        - Time: WSC, Man of the Half Century (Box 118, Folder 8)
        - Time Capsule, 1940 (Box 118, Folder 9)
        - Time Capsule, 1941 (Folder 10)
        - Time Capsule, 1942 (Box 118, Folder 11)
        - Time Capsule, 1943 (Box 118, Folder 12)
        - Time Capsule, 1944 (Box 118, Folder 13)
        - Time Capsule, 1945 (Box 118, Folder 14)
        - Time Capsule, 1950 (Box 118, Folder 15)
        - Time Capsule, 1956 (Box 118, Folder 16)
        - Time Capsule, 1959 (Box 118, Folder 17)
        - Time-Life (Box 118, Folder 18)
        - Tree: When the Moon Was High (Box 118, Folder 19)
        - Truman: Memoirs (Box 118, Folder 20)
        - Vansittart: The Mist Procession (Box 118, Folder 21)
        - War in the Desert (Box 119, Folder 1)
        - Warriors at Suez: Donald Neff (Box 119, Folder 2)
        - Wheeler-Bennett: Action This Day (Box 119, Folder 3)
        - Wilmot: The Struggle for Europe (Box 119, Folder 4)
        - Winant: A Letter from Grovesnor Square (Box 119, Folder 5)
        - Windsor: A King's Story (Box 119, Folder 6)
        - Winston Leonard Spencer Churchill (Box 119, Folder 7)
        - Winterbotham: The Ultimate Secret (Box 119, Folder 8)
        - The World Almanac 1940 (Box 119, Folder 9)
        - Wright: Dowding and the Battle of Britain (Box 119, Folder 10)
        - WSC (Box 119, Folder 11)
        - WSC: his complete speeches (Box 119, Folder 12)
        - WSC: military strategist? (Box 119, Folder 13)
        - W (Box 119, Folder 14)
        - Red-numbered series: 10, 11, 13, 14 (Box 120, Folder 1)
        - Red-numbered series: 33, 35-39 (Box 120, Folder 2)
        - Red-numbered series: 41, 44, 45, 48 (Box 120, Folder 3)
        - Red-numbered series: 50, 51, 69 (Box 120, Folder 4)
        - Red-numbered series: 70, 72, 74 (Box 120, Folder 5)
        - 1, 1A: 1890-1905 (Box 120, Folder 6)
        - 2: Dec 1906-Dec 1907 Pres Bd > Trade (Box 120, Folder 7)
        - 3: May 2, 1908-Feb 1911 Home Secy (Box 120, Folder 8)
        - 4: Oct 1911-May 1915 1st Lord > Admiralty (Box 120, Folder 9)
        - 5: May-Nov 1915 Duchy: then trenches (Box 120, Folder 10)
        - 6: July 1917-Jan 1919 Minister > Munitions (Box 120, Folder 11)
        - 7: Jan 1919-Feb 1921 Secy > Ste for War + Acr (Box 120, Folder 12)
        - 8: April 1921-Nov [19]24 In + Out (Box 120, Folder 13)
        - 9: Nov 1924-June 1929 Exchequer (Box 120, Folder 14)
        - Uncategorized research materials (Box 120, Folder 15)
        - Uncategorized research materials (Box 121, Folder 1-9)
      - Documents
        - Documents codes (Box 122, Folder 1)
        - 1-11, Roosevelt + Hopkins (Box 122, Folder 2-3)
        - 12-44, Wilmot (Box 122, Folder 4)
        - 45-51, Deakin (Box 122, Folder 5)
        - 52-54, Affectionately, FDR (Box 122, Folder 6)
        - 55-58, Crusade in Europe (Box 122, Folder 7)
        - 89-105, Goebbel's Diaries (Box 122, Folder 8)
        - 106-109, On Borrowed Time (Box 122, Folder 9)
        - 110-127, Collapse > 3rd Republic (Box 122, Folder 10)
        - 128-145, Prof + PM (Box 122, Folder 11)
        - 146-163, HST Memoirs (Box 123, Folder 1)
        - 164-183, Montgomery of Alamein (Box 123, Folder 2)
        - 184-206, MacMillan. Winds > Change (Box 123, Folder 3)
        - 207-218, R + Hopkins (text) (Box 123, Folder 4)
        - 219-245, Wavell (Box 123, Folder 5)
        - 256, Churchill's German Army (Box 123, Folder 6)
        - 257, Churchill's Indian Summer (Box 123, Folder 7)
        - 279-330 (Box 123, Folder 8)
        - 331-380 (Box 123, Folder 9)
        - 381-406 (Box 123, Folder 10)
        - 409-439 (Box 123, Folder 11)
        - 409-439 (Box 124, Folder 1)
        - 440-477 (Box 124, Folder 2)
        - 478-514 (Box 124, Folder 3-4)
        - 515, 1939 (Box 124, Folder 5)
        - 516-548, 1940 (Box 124, Folder 6)
        - 549-573, 1941 (Box 124, Folder 7)
        - 574-580, 1942 (Box 124, Folder 8)
        - 581-594, 1943 (Box 124, Folder 9)
        - 595-620, 1944 (Box 124, Folder 10)
        - 602-614, 1945 (Box 124, Folder 11)
        - 616, Character (Box 124, Folder 12)
      - Research notes
        These notes have been re-assembled from scattered locations. Gaps exist in the numbered pages.
        - pp. 1-65, The Biography of a Marriage (Box 124, Folder 13)
        - pp. 66-131, The Biography of a Marriage (Box 124, Folder 14)
        - pp. 158-164, Footprints in Time (Box 125, Folder 1)
        - pp. 171-183, Farewell the Trumpets (Box 125, Folder 2)
        - pp. 184-191, Churchill's Political Philosophy (Box 125, Folder 3)
        - pp. 193-199, Churchill's German Army (Box 125, Folder 4)
        - pp. 200-204, Berlin Diary (Box 125, Folder 5)
        - pp. 205-228, 1940 (Box 125, Folder 6)
        - pp. 229-234, A Churchill Family Album (Box 125, Folder 7)
        - pp. 428-457, Special Envoy to Churchill and Stalin (Box 125, Folder 8)
        - pp. 590-619, House of Lords Records Office (Box 125, Folder 9)
        - pp. 933-988, Their Finest Hour (Box 125, Folder 10)
        - pp. 989-1031, The Grand Alliance (Box 125, Folder 11)
        - pp. 1032-1079, The Hinge of Fate (Box 125, Folder 12)
        - pp. 1080-1115, Closing the Ring (Box 125, Folder 13)
        - pp. 1116-1155, Triumph and Tragedy (Box 125, Folder 14)
        - p. 1156, WSC on America and Britain (Box 125, Folder 15)
        - p. 1157, Life in Victorian England (Box 125, Folder 16)
        - pp. 1158-1173, Assignment: Churchill (Box 125, Folder 17)
        - pp. 1174-1230, WSC: The Era and the Man (Box 126, Folder 1)
        - pp. 1231-1258, Special Envoy to Curchill and Stalin (Box 126, Folder 2)
        - pp. 1259-1285: A Roving Commission (Box 126, Folder 3)
        - pp. 1286-1330, The Turn of the Tide (Box 126, Folder 4)
        - pp. 1331-1345, I Was WSC's Personal Secretary (Box 126, Folder 5)
        - pp. 1346-1355, WSC in Trial and Triumph (Box 126, Folder 6)
        - pp. 1495-1500, England, 1870-1914 (Box 126, Folder 7)
        - pp. 1501-1513, Victorians at Home and Away (Box 126, Folder 8)
        - pp. 1514-1537, Mid-Victorian Britain, 1851-1875 (Box 126, Folder 9)
        - pp. 1538-1549, Roosevelt and Hopkins (Box 126, Folder 10)
        - pp. 1550-1572, Pax Brittanica (Box 126, Folder 11)
        - pp. 1573-1628, Churchill by His Contemporaries (Box 126, Folder 12)
        - pp. 1629-1684, Irrepressible Churchill (Box 126, Folder 13)
        - pp. 1685-1694, Discovering Victorian London (Box 126, Folder 14)
        - pp. 1695-1743, Churchill: A Study in Failure (Box 126, Folder 15)
        - pp. 1761-1766, Victorian High Society (Box 126, Folder 16)
        - pp. 1767-1769, Life in Victorian England (Box 126, Folder 17)
        - pp. 1770-1793, The Fall of the British Empire (Box 127, Folder 1)
        - pp. 1794-1804, Victorian England (Box 127, Folder 2)
        - pp. 1805-1807, The Fall of the Dynasties (Box 127, Folder 3)
        - pp. 1808-1825, The Victorians: A World Built to Last (Box 127, Folder 4)
        - pp. 1845-1846, Longford: Wellington, Years of the Sword (Box 127, Folder 5)
        - pp. 1847-1869, Mr. Churchill's Secretary (Box 127, Folder 6)
        - pp. 1870-1879, The Art of the Possible (Box 127, Folder 7)
        - pp.1880-1891, Boothby: Recollections of a Rebel (Box 127, Folder 8)
        - pp. 1892-1914, Gallipoli (Box 127, Folder 9)
        - pp. 1915-1917, The English (Box 127, Folder 10)
        - pp. 1918-1922, London to Ladysmith via Pretoria (Box 127, Folder 11)
        - pp. 1923-1926, My Life and Loves (Box 127, Folder 12)
        - p. 1927, To Lose a Battle: France, 1940 (Box 127, Folder 13)
        - pp. 1928-1950, Simply Churchill (Box 127, Folder 14)
        - pp. 1951-1971, Churchill and the Dardanelles (Box 127, Folder 15)
        - pp. 1972-1973, A Churchill Canvas (Box 127, Folder 16)
        - pp. 1974-1980, A Concise History of the British Empire (Box 127, Folder 17)
        - pp. 1981-1988, A Letter from Grovesnor Square (Box 127, Folder 18)
        - pp. 1989-1991, Cradles of Eminence (Box 127, Folder 19)
        - pp. 1992-1994, The Victorian Temper (Box 127, Folder 20)
        - pp. 1995-2001, Winston Churchill and Harrow (Box 127, Folder 21)
        - pp. 2002-2005, Ian Hamilton's March (Box 127, Folder 22)
        - pp. 2025-2032, Churchill and Beaverbrook (Box 127, Folder 23)
        - p. 2033, The Rainbow Comes and Goes (Box 127, Folder 24)
        - pp. 2034-2036, The Churchill Legend (Box 127, Folder 25)
        - pp. 2037-2038, All About Winston Churchill (Box 127, Folder 26)
        - pp. 2039-2055, Winston Churchill (Box 127, Folder 27)
        - pp. 2056-2094, Churchill in Power (Box 127, Folder 28)
        - pp. 2095-2097, Autobiography of Margot Asquith, Vol. II (Box 127, Folder 29)
        - pp. 2098-2117, The Professor and the Prime Minister (Box 128, Folder 1)
        - pp. 2118-2120, Hitler and Russia (Box 128, Folder 2)
        - pp. 2121-2125, The River War (Box 128, Folder 3)
        - pp. 2126-2127, England from a Back Window (Box 128, Folder 4)
        - pp. 2128-2131, Rudyard Kipling (Box 128, Folder 5)
        - pp. 2132-2134, Heiresses and Coronets (Box 128, Folder 6)
        - pp. 2135-2139, The Memoirs of Lord Chandos (Box 128, Folder 7)
        - pp. 2140-2152, Churchill: A Profile (Box 128, Folder 8)
        - pp. 2154-2169, WSC: Servant of Crown and Commonwealth (Box 128, Folder 9)
        - pp. 2170-2182, Great Contemporaries (Box 128, Folder 10)
        - pp. 2183-2184, Savrola (Box 128, Folder 11)
        - pp. 2185-2186, My Diaries (Box 128, Folder 12)
        - p. 2187, Society in the Country House (Box 128, Folder 13)
        - pp. 2188-2192, Churchill: The Statesman and the Writer (Box 128, Folder 14)
        - pp. 2194-2211, Mr. Kipling's Army (Box 128, Folder 15)
        - pp. 2212-2228, The Churchill Years (Box 128, Folder 16)
        - p. 2229, Empire on the Seven Seas (Box 128, Folder 17)
        - pp. 2230-2281, Young Winston's Wars (Box 128, Folder 18)
        - pp. 2282-2290, The Oxford History of England (Box 128, Folder 19)
        - p. 2291, Our English Cousins (Box 128, Folder 20)
        - pp. 2292-2293, English Home Life (Box 128, Folder 21)
        - pp. 2296-2301, A Thread in the Tapestry (Box 128, Folder 22)
        - pp. 2302-2306, The Wit of Sir Winston (Box 128, Folder 23)
        - 1939 (Box 128, Folder 24)
        - Battle of Britain (Box 128, Folder 25)
        - Churchill: Their Finest Hour (Box 128, Folder 26-27)
        - Debbie Baker, 1980 May-1987 Apr (Box 129, Folder 1)
        - Jock Colville's diary (Box 129, Folder 2)
        - Deighton: Fighter (Box 129, Folder 3)
        - Deutscher: The Prophet Armed: Trotsky, 1879-1921 (Box 129, Folder 4)
        - Gilbert: Winston S. Churchill (Box 129, Folder 5-7)
        - Grigg: 1943, The Victory the Never Was (Box 130, Folder 1)
        - Honan: Return of the Battleship (Box 130, Folder 2)
        - Jones: A Diary With Letters (Box 130, Folder 3)
        - Klingman: 1941, Our Lives in a World on the Edge (Box 130, Folder 4)
        - Martin: Jennie I - pp. 1-16; Jennie II - pp. 1-33 (Box 130, Folder 5)
        - Memorandum to Mr. Manchester (Box 130, Folder 6)
        - Morris: Farewell the Trumpets (Box 130, Folder 7)
        - Montgomery: Memoirs (Box 130, Folder 8)
        - Roberts: Randolph: A Study of Churchill's Son (Box 130, Folder 9)
        - Taylor: Beaverbrook (Box 130, Folder 10)
        - Thompson: Sixty Minutes with Winston Churchill (Box 130, Folder 11)
        - Memoirs, Biographies etc.
          - Boothby: I Fight to Live (Box 130, Folder 12)
          - Churchill Papers (ChP); Cambridge (DB) (Box 130, Folder 13)
          - Man Who Flew Churchill; Churchillians (Box 130, Folder 14)
          - Pelling (Box 130, Folder 15)
          - Public Record Office [Kew](DB) (Box 130, Folder 16)
        - Summary of LNs 139-130 (Box 130, Folder 17)
        - Notes from clumps #18-20 (Box 130, Folder 18)
        - Notes from clumps #17-24 (Box 130, Folder 19)
        - Notes from clumps, mostly #19-26 (Box 130, Folder 20)
      - Interviews
        - Butler, Jeffrey, 1982 Apr (Box 131, Folder 1)
        - List of interviews, 1980-83 (Box 131, Folder 2)
        - Chips | Halle | Harrimans (Box 131, Folder 3)
        - Deakin | Southborough | Jane Williams | Graham Norton (Box 131, Folder 4)
        - Mary Soames | Strauss | Jock | Grigg (Box 131, Folder 5)
        - Fitzroy MacLean | Boothby | Bonham Carter | Lord Halisham (Box 131, Folder 6)
        - Di Cooper | Selkirk | Pitblado | John Martin (Box 131, Folder 7)
        - G.M Thompson | Va. Cowles | Chartwell (Box 131, Folder 8)
        - Mrs. Hill | Lady Avon | Malcolm MacDonald (Box 131, Folder 9)
        - Chimp | Oscar Nemon | R.L. James (Box 131, Folder 10)
        - Ian Jacob | Montague Browne | Tony Head (Box 131, Folder 11)
        - David Hunt | Annex | WSC II | Muggeridge | Lord Geoffrey Lloyd (Box 131, Folder 12)
        - A.J.P. Taylor | Vanda Salmon | MacMillan | Lord Butler (Rab) (Box 131, Folder 13)
        - George Malcolm Thompson? | Miscellaneous notes made in London (Box 131, Folder 14)
      - Working documents
        - Precis of a two-volume work (Box 131, Folder 15)
        - Codes - index of interviews (Box 131, Folder 16)
        - Codes - sources (Box 131, Folder 17)
        - Codes (Box 131, Folder 18-19)
        - WSC: traits and characteristics (Box 131, Folder 20)
        - Outlines (Box 131, Folder 21)
        - Clumps (Box 392-426)
        - WSC sources - general (Box 132, Folder 1)
        - Bibliographies and sources (Box 132, Folder 2)
        - Lion sources and acknowledgements (Box 132, Folder 3)
        - Working notes (Box 132, Folder 4-6)